Let's look at this little program.
It looks very similar to ones we've already seen.
It creates a variable and then assigns it a value over here.
Then there's an on of this.
event that allows the variable to increase by one every time the button is clicked.
Finally, we set the property of clicks, and that just lets us see how it's changing over
over time, and we've also got this watcher down here
so we can see how the value of clicks is changing.
But when we run it,
Something weird happens.
Over here, we're getting NAN, that stands for not a number.
And down here we're seeing that clicks isn't changing at all.
Now, the solution to fixing this problem is pretty easy,
and for now it's the only thing you're going to need to do.
If you switch over to text mode, this is even easier, you'll see that clicks is being created
here online
one, but we're also trying to recreate it on line three.
Go back into block mode.
Here's the program how we're used to seeing it, and it's not that different.
But suddenly our program runs as we want.
And we can see it both here and down here in the watch panel.
The reason that this is happening is because of a constant...
called scope. And without getting too into it, the basic idea is if you create
a variable inside of a block like on event and in particular
anything that has this function command, which you're going to learn more about
later in this year, it creates a variable that has local scope.
Local scope means that you can only use it in the space that it was created.
And that means anywhere inside of this on event.
Most variables we want
going to have global scope. It's best practice to create variables for now at
the beginning of your program like we did here on line one.
Eventually you're going to want to create some local variables.
For now we don't, and so you're going to need to debug programs the way we just did.
Make sure you're not using var.
inside of an on event, use your watch panel to see if strange things are
happening like a variable isn't changing when it looks like it should, and check
if you're getting weird outputs.
For example, like we got, not a number.
Later in the course, you'll learn more how to use this concept.
But for now,
For now, happy debugging and go catch some of those local variables to remove them from
your program.